Brandy LaVoy - Front End Web Developer

brandylavoy@gmail.com, 707-256-9108

github.com/brandylavoy, brandylavoy.github.io/portfolio/ linkedin.com/in/brandylavoy/

Summary

Front end developer candidate skilled in writing, clean, testable UI code. Experienced with React, jQuery, Node, vanilla JavaScript, and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. Experienced with modern tooling and excited to pick up the right skills for the job.

Skills

<u>Intermediate</u>: JavaScript, React, jQuery, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, REST APIs., MongoDB, Responsive mobile-first design, TDD with Mocha, Chai, webpack, Heroku, Single Page Applications, and ES6.

Expert: Written & verbal communication, teamwork, & problem-solving.

Recent Projects

BART Trip Planner: A full stack online public transit app that pulls BART train schedules from the BART.gov API. Built with React, Node, Express and MongoDB.

Running Event Finder: A full stack app that searches the active.com API for running events near the user's chosen location. Built using Node, Express and MongoDB.

Recipe Search: JavaScript app that pulls recipes from the Yummly API by keyword, dietary restrictions, or food allergies.

Experience

Scott Laboratories Petaluma, CA
Inside Technical Sales 5/2015 – Present

- Consult with customers over the phone explaining how to utilize the products that we sell
- Help customers troubleshoot issues with their wines
- Make product recommendations based on customer wine style targets
- Enter orders accurately in NAV
- ISO audit team member

Sonoma Wine Company

Laboratory Manager

American Canyon, CA 7/2013 – 2/2015

- Manage 2 laboratory techs maintaining the integrity of 500,000+ gallons of premium wine
- Analyze data generated by the techs accuracy accuracy, requested re-analysis as needed
- ISO audit team member
- Safety team member

Robert Mondavi Winery

Sr. Laboratory Technician

American Canyon, CA 8/2010 – 7/2013

- Ran lab analysis with a variety of automated lab instruments
- Performed preventative maintenance and troubleshooting work on all equipment
- Analyze data generated by the myself and the other techs for accuracy accuracy, requested re-analysis as needed

Franciscan Estate Winery (Temporary Position) Laboratory Technician	American Canyon, CA 4/2010 – 8/2010
 Ran lab analysis Performed lab preventative maintenance E&J Gallo Winery Enologist 	Fresno, CA 10/2008 – 2/2010
 Made all winemaking decisions for 20 million gallons of wine Michael Pozzan Winery Sales & Marketing 	Orinda, CA 9/2007 – 10/2008
 Sold wines to retail shops and restaurants Napa Wine Company Assistant Lab Manager 	Yountville, CA 3/2005 – 9/2007
 Managed the day-to-day activities of the laboratory Frank Family Vineyards Cellar/Lab Assistant 	Calistoga, CA 6/2005 – 6/2006
 Performed winery lab analysis and cellar operations William Hill Winery Special Event Coordinator 	Napa, CA 1/2005 – 6/2005
 Planned and coordinated special events Stonestreet Winery Seasonal Lab Technician 	Healdsburg, CA 9/2004 – 1/2005
 Performed harvest lab analysis Quintessa Winery Seasonal Tasting Room Associate 	Rutherford, CA 4/2004 – 9/2004

• Hosted visitors in the tasting room giving tours and tastings

Education

UNIVERSITY NAME

B.S. Psychology, Emphasis in Biology

GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

• Dean's Honor Roll

THINKFUL 6/2017

Web Development Intensive

- Completed intensive, six month course on modern full stack JavaScript development.
- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.